Guide to the Collection on Prominent Figures in Historical Recorded Sound
Yale University Music Library
Collection on prominent figures in historical recorded sound
1800-2000
MSS 103
Yale University Music Library
8.75
5 drawers, 3 boxes
This collection provides supplemental information on more than one thousand preeminent figures directly or indirectly related to historical sound recordings, mostly through photographs and other pictorial images, such as postcards and drawings, as well as through correspondence, clippings, articles, and other promotional material.
Scope and Contents
This collection was assembled at Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University, to provide supplementary information on, and pictorial images of, prominent figures associated with historical recorded sound. Over one thousand singers, composers, instrumentalists, actors and actresses, collectors, and others are represented. Individual files mostly include photographs, but occasionally there are correspondence and other documents from or pertaining to singers such as Jussi Björling, Lillian Blauvelt, Dame Clara Butt, Maria Callas, Emma Clavé, Feodor Chaliapin, Emmi Destin, Kirsten Flagstad, Beniamino Gigli, Selma Kurz, Blanche Marchesi, Nellie Melba, Ezio Pinza, Rosa Ponselle, and Blake Stern; composers such as Hector Berlioz, Arrigo Boito, Max Bruch, Léo Delibes, Pietri Mascagni, Jules Massenet, and Giacomo Puccini; conductors such as Sir John Barbirolli and Arturo Toscanini, the instrumentalists such as George Copeland, Dame Myra Hess, Wanda Landowska, Joseph Joachim, and Pablo de Sarasate; actresses such as Sarah Bernhardt and Ethel Barrymore; collectors such as Lawrence and Cora Witten, and many others.
The Lilli Lehmann, Victor Maurel, and Giuseppe Verdi files contain a number of handwritten correspondence by each person, many to each other.. Other items within the collection include letters and inscriptions to Madame Maurel from Lydia Lindgren and to Adelina Patti from Mr. Mario; a recording listing from Mado Robin; a manuscript of a musical excerpt from Arturo Toscanini; abulletin from the Vocal Record Collectors' Society concerning Jean de REszke; and extensive articles and other documents concerning Jean Sibelius. This collection also includes programs and promotional clippings, such as those found in Henry Irving's folder; articles in several languages, such as found in Heinrich Knote's and Lillian Nordica's folders; and sheet music books, such as found in Robert Stolz's folder.
Most of the photographs are either portraits or images of vocalists posed in operatic roles(such as found in Rene Maison's folder), both at a photo shoot and candid onstage.
Much of the material in the collection is undated, though many items may be traced empirically to the lifespan of their subject matter. Materials are undated unless otherwise specified.
Separated Materials
Most material on Enrico Caruso, Geraldine Farrar, and Adelina Patti have been removed and merged into separate collections (see MSS 100, Collection of Enrico Caruso caricatures, photographs, and other material; MSS 101, Collection of Geraldine Farrar correspondence and other material; MSS 102, Collection on Adelina Patti).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname.
Conductors (Music); Singers; Musicians; Composers; Correspondence; Photographs
- Names, Series I
  - Abarbanell, Lina (Folder 1)
  - Abel, 1886 (Folder 2)
  - Abendroth, Irene, 1908 (Folder 3)
  - Acerbi, Giuseppe (Folder 4)
  - Ackte, Aino, 1905 (Folder 5)
  - Adam, Adolphe (Folder 6)
  - Adami, Giuseppe, 1930 (Folder 7)
  - Adams, Maude, 1931 (Folder 8)
  - Adams, Suzanne (Folder 9)
  - Agussol, Charlotte (Folder 10)
  - Aki, Syoko (Folder 11)
  - Alard, Jean-Delphin (Folder 12)
  - Albani, Emma, 1890 (Folder 13)
  - Albani, Marie Luise, 1878–1930 (Folder 14)
  - Albeniz, Isacco (Folder 15)
  - Albers, Henri, 1906–1910 (Folder 16)
  - Alboni, Marietta (Folder 17)
  - Alda, Francis, 1905–1925 (Folder 18)
  - Aldighieri, Maria (Folder 19)
  - Allen, Viola, 1905 (Folder 20)
  - Alten, Bella, 1908 (Folder 21)
  - Althouse, Paul, 1913–1949 (Folder 22)
  - Altschuler, Modest (Folder 23)
  - Alvarez, Albert (Folder 24)
  - Alvars, Parish (Folder 25)
  - Alvary, Max, 1895 Mar 4 (Folder 26)
  - Amato, Pasquale (Folder 27)
  - Ananian, P. (Folder 28)
  - Ancona, Mario, 1881, 1896 (Folder 29)
  - Anday, Rosette, 1936 (Folder 30)
  - Anderson, Arthur, 1932 Feb 23 (Folder 31)
  - Anderson, Marian, 1964 (Folder 32)
  - Andreoli, Carlo (Folder 33)
  - Angerer, Margit (Folder 34)
  - Angliana, Giovanina (Folder 35)
  - Anitua, Fanny, 1926 Jun 1 (Folder 36)
  - Ansseau, Fernand, 1939 (Folder 37)
  - Anthes, George (Folder 38)
  - Apolloni, Giuseppe (Folder 39)
  - Arangi-Lombardi, Giannina, 1933 Dec 1 (Folder 40)
  - Archer, Friedrich (Folder 41)
  - Arditi, Luigi (Folder 42)
  - Arimondi, Vittorio (Folder 43)
  - Arikel, Teresa (Folder 44)
  - Arnoldson-Fischhof, Sigrid, 1889–1931 (Folder 45)
  - Arral, Blanche (Folder 46)
  - Arthur, Julia, 1925 (Folder 47)
  - Asioli, Bonifaio (Folder 48)
  - Auber, Daniel François Esprit (Folder 49)
  - Austin (Folder 50)
  - Austral, Florence, 1932 (Folder 51)
  - Bada, Angelo, 1912 Mar 19 (Folder 52)
    Scope and Contents
    One photo of house/land.
  - Bahr-Mildenberg, Anna (Folder 53)
  - Baklanoff, George (Folder 54)
  - Balbo, Marie (Folder 55)
  - Bandrowski, Alexander (Folder 56)
  - Barbacini, E. (Folder 57)
  - Barbieri-Nini, Marianna (Folder 58)
  - Barbirolli, Sir John, 1942, 1970 (Folder 59)
  - Bardelli, Cesare, 1964 (Folder 60)
  - Barrientos, Maria (Folder 61)
  - Barrientos, Maria, 1910–1918 (Box 6, Folder 1071)
    Oversize.
  - Barrymore, Ethel (Folder 62)
  - Bars, Jacques (Folder 63)
  - Bary, Alfred von (Folder 64)
  - Baseri, Abramo, 1862 (Folder 65)
  - Basiola, Mario, 1929 (Folder 66)
  - Bassermann, Adolf (Folder 67)
  - Bassi, Amadeo, 1899–1908 (Folder 68)
  - Bassi, Nicola (Folder 69)
  - Battistini, Mattia, 1910–1930 (Folder 70)
  - Battistini, Mattia, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1072)
  - Batz, Reinhold (Folder 71)
  - Bauer, Harold (Box 6, Folder 1073)
  - Bauermeister, Mathilde (Folder 72)
  - Bazzini, Antonio (Folder 73)
  - Becker, Hugo (Folder 74)
  - Becucci, Ernesto (Folder 75)
  - Beecham, Thomas (Folder 76)
  - Bellaigue, Camille, 1920 (Folder 77)
  - Bellezza, Vincenzo, 1929 Apr 11 (Folder 78)
  - Bellincioni, Gemma, 1890, 1933 (Folder 79)
  - Bellison, Simeon, 1949 (Folder 80)
  - Bender, Paul (Folder 81)
  - Berger, Erna, 1952–1953 (Folder 82)
  - Berger, Rudolf, 1912 (Folder 83)
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1970 (Folder 84)
  - Bernhardt, Sarah (Folder 85)
  - Bertram, Theodore (Folder 86)
  - Bettefini, Giovanni (Folder 87)
  - Bevignani, Enrico, 1903 (Folder 88)
  - Biancolini-Rodriquez, Marietta (Folder 89)
  - Birrenkoven, Willy (Folder 90)
  - Bispham, David, 1902 (Folder 91)
  - Bistosi, Adelaide, 1901 (Folder 92)
  - Bizet, Georges, 1916-1917, 1981 (Folder 93)
  - Björling, Jussi, 1918, 1960 (Folder 94)
  - Bjurstraum, Harold (Folder 95)
  - Black, Andrew, 1900 (Folder 96)
  - Blancard, Nady, 1907 (Folder 97)
  - Blass, Robert, 1910 (Folder 98)
  - Blauvelt, Lillian, 1900 (Folder 99)
  - Blech, Leo (Folder 100)
  - Blumenthal, Giacamo (Folder 101)
  - Boccabadati, Verginia, 1850 (Folder 102)
  - Bockelmann, Rudolf (Folder 103)
  - Bohnen, Michael, 1957 (Folder 104)
  - Boieldieu, Adrien (Folder 105)
  - Boieldieu and Auber (Box 6, Folder 1074)
  - Boito, Arrigo (Folder 106)
  - Bokor, Margit, 1937 (Folder 107)
  - Bollmann, Heinz (Folder 108)
  - Boltenhagen, Curt, 1909 (Folder 109)
  - Bolz, Oskar (Folder 110)
  - Bonci, Alessandro, 1907–1909 (Folder 111)
  - Bonci, Alessandro, 1905–1910 (Box 6, Folder 1075)
  - Bonelli, Richard, 1933 (Folder 112)
  - Bonini, Francesco Maria (Folder 113)
  - Bordes, Charles (Folder 114)
  - Borgatti, Giuseppe, 1897, 1933 (Folder 115)
  - Borghl-Mamo, Adelaide, 1930 (Folder 116)
  - Bori, Lucrezia, 1951 May 10 (Folder 117)
  - Bork, Alice (Folder 118)
  - Borsi, Teresa de Giuli, 1849 (Folder 119)
  - Bos, Coenraad, 1942 Sep 7 (Folder 120)
  - Boschetti, Amina (Folder 121)
  - Bossi, Enrico (Folder 122)
  - Bossi, Renzo (Folder 123)
  - Botteno, Alisandro, 1930 (Folder 124)
  - Bottesini, Giovanni (Folder 125)
  - Botti, Candida, 1883 (Folder 126)
  - Bourbon (Folder 127)
  - Bouy, Samuel (Folder 128)
  - Boyer, Lucienne (Folder 129)
  - Braga, Gaetano (Folder 130)
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1896 (Folder 131)
  - Brambilla-Ponchielli, Theresa, 1878 (Folder 132)
  - Brandt-Forster, Ellen, 1902 (Folder 133)
  - Bandt, Marianne, 1886 (Folder 134)
  - Branzell, Karin, 1930 Feb 20 (Folder 135)
  - Branzell, Karin (Box 6, Folder 1076)
  - Brejean-Silver, Georgette (Folder 136)
  - Brema, Marie (Folder 137)
  - Bressler-Gianoli, Clotilde (Folder 138)
  - Breuer, Hans, 1910–1916 (Folder 139)
  - Breual, Lucienne (Folder 140)
  - Briccialdi, Giulio (Folder 141)
  - Briesemeister, Otto (Folder 142)
  - Brownlee, John (Folder 143)
  - Brozel, Philip (Folder 144)
  - Bruch, Max, 1930 (Folder 145)
  - Bruno (Folder 146)
  - Buck, Dudley (Folder 147)
  - Bull, Ole (Folder 148)
  - Bulli-Paoli, Marietta, 1872 (Folder 149)
  - Bulow, Hans von, 1871 (Folder 150)
  - Buonomici, 1930 (Folder 151)
  - Burgstaller, Alois, 1901–1904 (Folder 152)
  - Burgstaller, Alois, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 1077)
  - Burmester, Willy (Folder 153)
  - Burrian, Carl, 1909 Jan 15 (Folder 154)
  - Burzio, Eugenia (Folder 155)
  - Burzio, Eugenia, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 1078)
  - Busch, Lotte Gadski (Folder 156)
  - Butt, Dame Clara, 1910 (Folder 157)
  - Buxtehude, Dieterich (Box 6, Folder 1079)
  - Buzzi-Peccia, Arturo (Folder 158)
  - Buzzola, Antonio (Folder 159)
  - Cahier, Sara Jane layton Walker, 1910 (Folder 160)
  - Caliga, Fritz (Folder 161)
  - Callas, Maria, 1974 (Folder 162)
  - Calvé, Emma, 1891–1930 (Folder 163)
  - Calvé, Emma, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 1080)
  - Campana, Fabio (Folder 164)
  - Campanari, Giuseppe, 1903 Apr 15 (Folder 165)
  - Campanini, Cleofonte, 1905 Jul 21 (Folder 166)
  - Campanini, Italo, 1930 (Folder 167)
  - Campora, Giuseppe, 1955 (Folder 168)
  - Cannetti, Linda (Folder 169)
  - Capocci, Filippo (Folder 170)
  - Capoul, Victor (Folder 171)
  - Caracciolo, Luigi (Folder 172)
  - Carelli, Emma (Folder 173)
  - Caron, Rose, 1892 (Folder 174)
  - Caron, Rose, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 1081)
  - Carpi, Fernando, 1907 (Folder 175)
  - Carré, Marguerite (Folder 176)
  - Carreño, Teresa (Folder 177)
  - Carteri, Rosanna (Folder 178)
  - Carvalho, Carolina, 1931 (Folder 179)
  - Casamorata, Luigi (Folder 180)
  - Case, Anna (Folder 181)
  - Casella, Carlo (Folder 182)
  - Casella, Cesare, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 1082)
  - Casset (Folder 183)
  - Catalani, Alfredo (Folder 184)
  - Cataneo, Aurelia (Folder 185)
  - Cavalieri, Lina, 1908–1910 (Folder 186)
  - Cavallini, Ernesto, 1933 (Folder 187)
  - Cebotari, Maria, 1932 (Folder 188)
  - Cerlo, Andreoli (Folder 189)
  - Cervi-Caroli, Ersilia (Folder 190)
  - Cesi, Beniamino (Folder 191)
  - Chabrier, Emanuele, 1937 (Folder 192)
  - Chaliapin, Feodor, 1924 (Folder 193)
  - Charbonnel, Marie (Folder 194)
  - Charpentier, Gustave (Folder 195)
  - Chemet, Renee (Folder 196)
  - Cherubini, Luigi (Folder 197)
  - Chevillard, Camille, 1910 (Folder 198)
  - Chookasian, Lili (Folder 199)
  - Ciardi, César (Folder 200)
  - Cimarosa, Domenico (Folder 201)
  - Ciro, Pinzuti (Folder 202)
  - Clairmont, Eva, 1912 (Folder 203)
  - Clemens, Clara, 1926 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 1085)
  - Clément, Edmond (Folder 204)
  - Coates, John, 1915 (Folder 205)
  - Coccia, Carlo, 1932 (Folder 206)
  - Coghlan, Rose (Folder 207)
  - Cohen, Harriet, 1964 (Folder 208)
  - Cole, Belle (Folder 209)
  - Collins, Janet (Box 6, Folder 1083)
  - Colonne, Edouardo (Folder 210)
  - Colzani, Anselmo (Folder 211)
  - Constantino, Florencio, 1906 Feb 12 (Folder 212)
  - Contiguglia, Richard and John (Folder 213)
  - Copeland, George (Folder 214)
  - Corena, Fernando (Folder 215)
  - Costa, Mario (Folder 216)
  - Costa, Mario, 1910 Sep 2 (Box 6, Folder 1084)
  - Cotogni, Antonio, 1874–1918 (Folder 217)
  - Crabbe, Armand, 1928–1929 (Folder 218)
  - Crescentina, Adolfo (Folder 219)
  - Crescentini, Girolamo (Folder 220)
  - Crooks, Richard, 1937 (Folder 221)
  - Cui, Cesar (Folder 222)
  - Culp, Julia (Folder 223)
  - Currier, Donald (Folder 224)
  - Curzon, Clifford (Folder 225)
  - D'Albert, Eugen (Folder 226)
  - Dalla, Rizza (Folder 227)
  - Dalmores, Charles, 1908 (Folder 228)
  - D'Alvarez, Marguerite (Folder 229)
  - Damoreau, Laura Cynthie (Folder 230)
  - Damrosch, Leopold (Folder 231)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1897 Apr 6 (Folder 232)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 1086)
  - Dancla, Charles (Folder 233)
  - D'Andrade, Francisco, 1892 (Folder 234)
  - Dani, Carlo (Folder 235)
  - D'Arcelee, Hariclee, 1895 (Folder 236)
  - Darnton, Leo (Folder 237)
  - D'Arcais, Francesco (Folder 238)
  - D'Arclee, Hariclea (Folder 239)
  - D'Assy, Pierre, 1906 (Folder 240)
  - Davenny, Ward (Folder 241)
  - David, Ferdinand (Folder 242)
  - David, Giovanni (Folder 243)
  - David, Leon (Folder 244)
  - Davies, Ben (Folder 245)
  - Davies, Fanny (Folder 246)
  - Dawson, Frederick (Folder 247)
  - De La Tour, Imbart (Folder 248)
  - De Angelis, Nazzareno (Folder 249)
  - De Bassini, Alberto (Folder 250)
  - Debicka, Hedwig von, 1933 (Folder 251)
  - De Bidoli, Emi, 1940 (Folder 252)
  - Decker, Jacques (Folder 253)
  - De Fauus, Desire (Folder 254)
  - De Grecis, Nicola (Folder 255)
  - De Hildago, Elvira, 1922 (Folder 256)
  - Delagrange, Anna, 1846 (Box 6, Folder 1087)
  - De Los Angeles, Victoria (Folder 257)
  - DeKoven, Reginald (Folder 258)
  - Delibes, Léo, 1885, 1899 (Folder 259)
  - De L'isle, Marie (Folder 260)
  - Delius, Elizabeth, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 1088)
  - Delius, Frederick (Folder 261)
  - Della Santa, Lotte (Folder 262)
  - De Luca, Giuseppe, 1903, 1949 (Folder 263)
  - De Lucia, Fernando, 1916 Dec 14 (Folder 264)
  - De Lussan, Zelie (Box 6, Folder 1089)
  - Delmas, Jean-Francois, 1908 (Folder 265)
  - De-Macchi, Maria (Folder 266)
  - Demougeot, Marcelle (Folder 267)
  - Demuth, Leopold (Folder 268)
  - De Muro, Bernardo, 1945 (Folder 269)
  - Denza, Luigi (Folder 270)
  - Derivis, Maria, 1877 Mar 27 (Folder 271)
  - DeSegurola, Andrés (Folder 272)
  - Destinn, Emmy, 1907–1913 (Folder 273)
  - Destinn, Emmy (Box 6, Folder 1090)
  - Didur, Adam, 1929 (Folder 274)
  - D'Indy, Vincent (Folder 275)
  - Di Marchi (Folder 276)
  - Dippel, Andreas (Folder 277)
  - Donalda, Pauline, 1962 July 15 (Folder 278)
  - Donaudy, Stefano (Folder 279)
  - Donekoy (Folder 280)
  - Donizetti, Giuseppe (Box 6, Folder 1091)
  - Donzelli, Demenico (Folder 281)
  - D'Ormeville, Carlo (Folder 282)
  - Dornay, Louis, 1922 (Folder 283)
  - Dufay, Guillaume (Folder 284)
  - Dufranne, Hector, 1910 (Folder 285)
  - Duprez, Luigi (Folder 286)
  - Duprez, Gilbert (Folder 287)
  - Durand, Auguste (Folder 288)
  - Duse, Eleanora, 1890 (Folder 289)
  - Dyck, Ernest, van, 1892 (Folder 290)
  - Eames, Emma, 1891–1909 (Folder 291)
  - Eames, Emma, 1907–1908 (Box 6, Folder 1092)
  - Easton, Florence (Folder 292)
  - Edel, Alfredo, 1896 (Folder 293)
  - Edvina, Louise (Folder 294)
  - Eichenwald, Margaret (Folder 295)
  - Edward, Elgar, 1902 Jun 30 (Folder 296)
  - Elizza, Elise, 1901 (Folder 297)
  - Endert, Elisabeth Bohm van (Folder 298)
  - Engelhardt (Folder 299)
  - Erb, Karl (Folder 300)
  - Ercolani, Remo (Folder 301)
  - Erlanger, Camille (Folder 302)
  - Ernst, Heirich Wilhelm (Folder 303)
  - Eschmann, Gian-Carlo, 1885 (Folder 304)
  - Esseu, Maria von, 1932 (Folder 305)
  - Essipoua, Anna (Folder 306)
  - Esty, Alice (Folder 307)
  - Everardi, Camillo, 1875 (Folder 308)
  - Faccio, Franco (Folder 309)
  - Fagoaga, Isidoro (Folder 310)
  - Fairchild, Blair (Folder 311)
  - Fancourt, Darrell (Folder 312)
  - Farneti, Maria (Folder 313)
  - Felix, Benedict, 1905 (Folder 314)
  - Feodoroff, Georges (Folder 315)
  - Feraldy, Germaine (Folder 316)
  - Ferenczy, Oto (Folder 317)
  - Ferguson, Catherine (Folder 318)
  - Ferrari-Fontana, Edoardo, 1914 (Folder 319)
  - Ferraris, Inez [Maria], 1904–1914 (Folder 320)
  - Ferrero, Willy, 1906–1912 (Folder 321)
  - Fielitz, Alexander von (Folder 322)
  - Frangcon-Davies (Folder 323)
  - Fignor, Nikolai Nikolaevich (Folder 324)
  - Filippi, Filippo (Folder 325)
  - Filipponi, Dina (Folder 326)
  - Finzi-Magrini, Giuseppina (Folder 327)
  - Fiovante, Vincenzo (Folder 328)
  - Fitziu, Anna (Folder 329)
  - Flagstad, Kirsten, 1957 Sep 12 (Folder 330)
  - Fleischer, Editha, 1929 (Folder 331)
  - Fleischer-Edel, Katherine (Folder 332)
  - Flon, Philippe (Folder 333)
  - Floridia, Pietro (Folder 334)
  - Florjanski, Vladislav (Folder 335)
  - Flotow, Friedrich (Folder 336)
  - Förstel, Gertrude, 1910 (Folder 337)
  - Förster-Lauterer, Berta (Folder 338)
  - Forbes, Robertson (Box 6, Folder 1093)
  - Forchhammer, Ejnar, 1902 (Folder 339)
  - Fornia, Rita, 1912 (Folder 340)
  - Forst, Grete, 1940 (Folder 341)
  - Francesco, Durante (Folder 342)
  - Franchetti, Alberto, 1902 (Folder 343)
  - Franci, Benvenuto, 1930 Mar 15 (Folder 344)
  - Francillo-Kauffmann, Hedwig (Folder 345)
  - Franck, Cesar (Folder 346)
  - Franko, Nathan (Folder 347)
  - Franko, Sam, 1902 Sep 4 (Box 7, Folder 1094)
  - Franz, Robert (Folder 348)
  - Fraschini, Gaetano (Folder 349)
  - Fremstad, Olive, circa 1905 (Folder 350)
  - Fremstad, Olive (Box 7, Folder 1095)
  - Fricci, Antoinette, 1874, 1908 (Folder 351)
  - Frick, Claire (Folder 352)
  - Fried, Oscar (Folder 353)
  - Frimi, Rudolf (Folder 354)
  - Fuchs, Alberto (Folder 355)
  - Fuchs, Marta, 1934 (Folder 356)
  - Fugere, Lucien (Folder 357)
  - Fumagalli, Adolfo (Folder 358)
  - Fursch-Madi (Folder 359)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip and Clara Clemens, 1925–1928 (Folder 360)
  - Gadski, Johanna, 1928 (Folder 361)
  - Gaetano, Fraschini (Folder 362)
  - Gailhard, Pedro (Folder 363)
  - Galeffi, Carlo, 1922 (Folder 364)
  - Galletti (Folder 365)
  - Galletti, Cesare (Folder 366)
  - Galli-Curci, Amelita, 1914–1922 (Folder 367)
  - Gallos, Hermann, 1918 (Folder 368)
  - Galofre, B., 1889 (Folder 369)
  - Ganne, Luigi (Folder 370)
  - Gantenberg-Oehlschläger, Edwiga (Folder 371)
  - Garbin, Edoardo, 1905 Feb 14 (Folder 372)
  - Garcia, Eugenia (Folder 373)
  - Garcia, Manuel, 1901 (Folder 374)
  - Garcia, Maria Malibran (Folder 375)
  - Garcia, Pauline Viardot (Folder 376)
  - Garden, Mary (Folder 377)
  - Garden, Mary (Box 7, Folder 1096)
  - Garetti, Maria, 1907 Feb 13 (Folder 378)
  - Gasperoni, Enrico (Folder 379)
  - Gates, Lucy, 1930 (Folder 380)
  - Gauley, Marie-Therese (Folder 381)
  - Gauthier, Eva (Folder 382)
  - Gauwin, Adolphe, 1903 (Folder 383)
  - Gayarre, Giuliano, 1988 (Folder 384)
  - Gazzaniga, Marietta (Box 7, Folder 1097)
  - Gedda, Nicolai (Folder 385)
  - Gerhardt, Elena (Folder 386)
  - Gerhardt, Maria, 1932 (Folder 387)
  - Gerhäuser, Emil (Folder 388)
  - German, Edward (Folder 389)
  - Gerville-Reache (Folder 390)
  - Gevaert, Francois-Auguste (Folder 391)
  - Ghizlanzoni, Antonio (Folder 392)
  - Giannini, Dusolina, 1905 (Folder 393)
  - Gigli, Beniamino, 1919–1955 (Folder 394)
  - Gilibert, Charles and Gabrielle Lejeune (Folder 395)
  - Gilbert, William S., 1881 May 21 (Box 7, Folder 1098)
  - Gilion, Mario (Folder 396)
  - Gillette, William (Folder 397)
  - Gilliland, Helen (Folder 398)
  - Gilmore, Patrick S. (Folder 399)
  - Giordano, Umberto (Folder 400)
  - Giorga, Paolo (Folder 401)
  - Giorgetti, Ferdinando (Folder 402)
  - Giosa, Nicola de (Folder 403)
  - Giraldoni, Eugenio, 1900 Oct 19 (Folder 404)
  - Girardi, Alexander (Folder 405)
  - Giudice, Maria (Folder 406)
  - Gladstone, William (Folder 407)
  - Gleason, Helen (Folder 408)
  - Gluck, Alma, 1919 (Folder 409)
  - Godard, Benjamin (Folder 410)
  - Godefroid, Felix (Folder 411)
  - Godowsky, Leopold, 1915 Dec 25 (Folder 412)
  - Goetze, Marie, 1905 (Folder 413)
  - Gogorza, Emilio de, 1925–1927 (Folder 414)
  - Goldmark, Carl (Folder 415)
  - Golinelli, Stefano, 1881 (Folder 416)
  - Goltz, Alfred (Folder 417)
  - Gomes, Antonio, circa 1972 (Folder 418)
  - Gomes, Carlos (Folder 419)
  - Gonzaga, Aida (Folder 420)
  - Gordigiani, Luigi (Folder 421)
  - Gordon, Cyrena van, 1929 (Folder 422)
  - Gordon, Jeanne (Folder 423)
  - Goritz, Otto, 1912 (Folder 424)
  - Gounod, Charles (Folder 425)
  - Grabczewski (Folder 426)
  - Gramophone Co., 1902–1903 (Folder 427)
  - Grandjean, Louise (Folder 428)
  - Granville, Sidney (Folder 429)
  - Grassini, Giuseppina (Folder 430)
  - Grau, Robert (Folder 431)
  - Greenwood, Charlotte, circa 1940 (Folder 432)
  - Grengg, Carl (Folder 433)
  - Gretry, Andrea (Folder 434)
  - Grietzinger, Eduard (Folder 435)
  - Griffin, Elsie (Folder 436)
  - Grisi, Giulia (Folder 437)
  - Griswold, Putnam (Folder 438)
  - Gröbke, Adolf (Folder 439)
  - Grossmith, George (Folder 440)
  - Grünfeld, Heinrich, 1898 Feb 15 (Folder 441)
  - Grüning, Wilhelm, 1894–1902 (Folder 442)
  - Günther, Mizzi, 1907 Feb 19 (Folder 443)
  - Guercia, Mille (Folder 444)
  - Guetter, Walter (Folder 445)
  - Gulbranson, Ellen (Folder 446)
  - Gura-Hummel, Annie (Folder 447)
  - Gutheil-Schoder, Marie, 1910–1918 (Folder 448)
  - Haberl, Benno (Folder 449)
  - Hackett, Charles (Folder 450)
  - Hading, Jane (Folder 451)
  - Hafgren, Lilly, 1920 Jun 13 (Folder 452)
  - Hagen, Adolf (Folder 453)
  - Hailbrun, S. (Folder 454)
  - Haleuy, Jacques F. (Folder 455)
  - Hall, Marie, 1904 (Folder 456)
  - Hanke, Jeno, 1888 Jun 17 (Folder 457)
  - Hansen, Paul (Folder 458)
  - Harris, Augustus, 1891 (Folder 459)
  - Hartingson, Frits, 1872 Sep 7 (Folder 460)
  - Hartoulary-Darclée (Folder 461)
  - Hasselmans, Louis, 1929 (Folder 462)
  - Hauk, Minnie (Folder 463)
  - Hauman, Thomas, 1834 (Folder 464)
  - Haydter, Alexander, 1916 (Folder 465)
  - Hayes, Roland, 1955 Aug 1 (Folder 466)
  - Heilbron, Marie (Folder 467)
  - Helena, Edith, 1951 (Folder 468)
  - Heller, Stefan (Folder 469)
  - Helm, Kraemer (Folder 470)
  - Hempel, Frieda, 1920–1956 (Folder 471)
  - Hempel, Frieda (Box 7, Folder 1099)
  - Henschel, George (Folder 472)
  - Hensel, Heinrich (Folder 473)
  - Herold, Vilhelm, 1907 (Folder 474)
  - Herz, Henri (Folder 475)
  - Hesch, Wilhelm (Folder 476)
  - Hess, Dame Myra, 1920 (Folder 477)
  - Hilgermann, Laura, 1910 (Folder 478)
  - Hillebrandt, Tessie (Folder 479)
  - Hiller, Ferdinand (Folder 480)
  - Hinckley, Elizabeth S., 1956 (Folder 481)
    Wife of Alan Carter Hinckley.
  - Hines, Jerome (Folder 482)
  - Hinrichs, Gustav (Folder 483)
  - Hochheim, Paul (Folder 484)
  - Hofmann, Ludwig (Folder 485)
  - Hohenfels, Perdita (Folder 486)
  - Homer, Louise, 1912 (Folder 487)
  - Honneger, Arthur (Folder 488)
  - Huberman, Bronislaw (Folder 489)
  - Huen, Julius, 1936 Apr 28 (Box 7, Folder 1100)
  - Hüsch, Gerhard, 1937-1938, 1970 (Folder 490)
  - Hummel, Johann Nepomuck (Folder 491)
  - Humperdinck, Engelbert (Folder 492)
  - Hutt, Robert (Folder 493)
  - Irving, Henry, 1879 (Folder 494)
  - Ivogün, Maria (Folder 495)
  - Jadlowker, Hermann (Folder 496)
  - Jaell, Alfred (Folder 497)
  - Jagel, Frederick, 1929 (Folder 498)
  - Jahn, Wilhelm (Folder 499)
  - Janis, Elsie (Folder 500)
  - Januschowsky, Georgine von (Folder 501)
  - Jefferson, Joseph, 1887–1892 (Folder 502)
  - Jepson, Helen, 1937 May 2 (Folder 503)
  - Jeritza, Maria (Folder 504)
  - Joachim, Joseph, 1831 (Folder 505)
  - Jörn, Karl, 1910 (Folder 506)
  - Johnson, Edward, 1908, 1959 (Folder 507)
  - Jomelli, Jeanne (Folder 508)
  - Jomelli, Jeanne (Box 7, Folder 1101)
  - Joseffy, Raphael, 1853 (Folder 509)
  - Josephi, Josef, 1919 Apr 8 (Folder 510)
  - Journet, Marcel, 1903 Apr 16 (Folder 511)
  - Juch, Emma (Folder 512)
  - Kalkbreuner, Friedrich Wilhelm (Folder 513)
  - Kalter, Sabine, 1914 Apr 24 (Folder 514)
  - Kappel, Gertrude, 1960 (Folder 515)
  - Karola, Amelia (Folder 516)